Andrew Sibiriakov

+1 832-457-9872

andrey.sibiriakov@gmail.com

www.andrew-sib.com



Summary .

Front-end developer with extensive experience in building complex applications since 2019. Interested in developing a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks. The main objective is to achieve the highest quality of delivered product. An active participant in the "Codewars" demonstrating a genuine passion for programming. Striving to expanding knowledge and mastering new concepts and new technologies. Has a mentoring experience and willingness to support others. Conscientious and reliable teammate.

Professional Experience _____

ChipAssist Switzerland

Front-end developer

Apr 2021 - Jun 2024

- Developed a marketplace utilizing React.js, Redux and TypeScript, that has grown up to 1000+ active users.
- The page **loading speed has been increased from 6-8 sec to 1.5-2 sec** through splitting on lightweight chunks, memoization and code refactoring and optimization.
- Built a stock exchange platform **connecting 100+ sellers** around the world.
- Created a complex chat system allowing communication and purchase order processing.
- Designed and developed own admin panel for associates.
- Mentoring junior specialists.
- Unit testing utilizing Jest and Behave, deployment to production.

Event Platform

May 2019 - Apr 2021

Front-end developer

- Maintenance of a web app for online events, which includes live streaming, a chat box, and other interactives such as voting, surveys, and quizzes, resulted in a **30% boost in conversions**.
- Developed web dynamic websites and landing pages utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, resulted in a **50%** increase in user engagement in the event platform.
- · Created graphic and video content
- · Content management

Education

Moscow Technical University of Communications and Informatics

Sep 2018 - Jul 2022

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science

IT-incubator

Jan 2020 - May 2021

React front-end development course www.it-incubator.io

Skills

Program languages: JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript

Frameworks: React.js, Next.js
State managment: Redux, MobX

Style libraries: Material ui, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Styled Components, GSAP (GreenSock)

Other technologies: REST APIs, Axios, Sentry, Storybook, Webpack, Gulp, Docker, NPM, Git, Jira,

Atlassian, Jest